Anthony Awuni

Applications & Product Support | Entry Level Front End - React | PMP Candidate | Esports | Radio | Content Production

Accra Ghana | +233202090340 | awenjab2011@gmail.com

Summary

My friends describe me as a problem solver with extensive experience in Customer Service, Product Development, and Digital Commerce. An entry level web developer(I guess I have always loved the tech space) focused on front-end with React. Currently a PMP Candidate set to take my exam mid 2023.

If I had a superpower, it would be the ability to influence my surroundings. Whereas a superhero might be able to control the elements, I would be good at persuasion. I can put a grumpy customer at ease. Is it possible for me to be flexible and adaptable as well? Even if I lack shapeshifting abilities, I am capable of tackling new tasks and responsibilities in a way that will allow me to thrive in a fast-changing environment. I'll be known as Agility Man. Lol. Scrum and sprint planning are my specialty.

Skills

- Jira
- Freshdesk
- Intercom
- Django admin
- Team Leadership

- Project Management
- Scrum Processes and Agile Best Practices
- Product / Software Development
- Customer Support
- Dealing with irate customers

Experience

CUSTOMER SUCCESS COORDINATOR | 02/2023 - Current

Rising Academy Network - Accra

Remote

- Oversee entire customer support team.
- Ensured near-real-time response to all B2C customers on (Rising Academy Network's Math Tutor Software).
- Improved end-of-cycle satisfaction for product users.
- Maximizing customer outcomes and decrease our time-to-value for .
- Harnessing automation to Increase user engagement on.

SENIOR PRODUCT OPERATIONS ASSOCIATE | 02/2023 - Current

Mpharma - Accra, Ghana

Remote

- Project manager for Bloom integration(mPharma's proprietary retail and pharmacy transformation tool), implementation and adoption into new markets and facilities across regions.
- Developed documentation for process flow and unboarding of different business types into bloom across markets.
- Setting and reporting on SLAs to ensure process measurement, outcome, and overall improvement.

PRODUCT SUPPORT ASSOCIATE | 01/2022 - 02/2023

mPharma - Accra, Ghana

Remote

- Reduced the median first response time from 32 minutes and 11 seconds to under 5 minutes in the first quarter of 2022 and consistently maintained this mark.
- Achieved and maintained a CST score of 90% or higher through intercom while providing excellent user support.
- Leveraged on agile methodologies (Scrum, Sprints) to work on improvements, bug fixes, new features and enhancements of Bloom, mPharma's proprietary retail and pharmacy transformation software. This is based on user feedback and continues testing of the product.
- Working with Engineering, Product, Supply Chain, and other internal teams to troubleshoot and solve technical user problems
- Manage the global product support
- Troubleshoot user issues reported via Bloom help or other channels from across the market
- Follow standard procedures for proper escalation of unresolved issues to the appropriate internal teams
- Train users and set up new facilities on Bloom
- Drive the creation of our support documentation and processes to improve users' experiences and help scale our operations
- Provide on-site service to facilities within the country for training, support, or on-site troubleshooting as needed
- Continuously improve the global processes and ensure consistency in support across countries

REMOTE CUSTOMER SUPPORT AGENT | 09/2020 - 06/2021

5CA - Accra. Netherlands

• Email Support Tickets and Live Chats for Secretlab Gaming Chairs.

REMOTE DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST | 06/2019 - 07/2020

Wishpond Technologies - Vancouver, Canada

- Remote (WFH in Ghana) Online Campaign Design and Implementation, Leads
- Generation, Email Automation, ROI, Facebook and Google Ads, Website Tracking and Analytic, Proposal Writing
- Successfully handled 10 15 clients at a time.

COMMUNICATIONS ANALYST FOR TOBI CHATBOT | 01/2019 - 11/2019

Vodafone Ghana - Accra, Ghana

- Data Input for TOBi Chatbot.
- Training and Machine Learning for TOBi Chatbot using IMB Watson.
- Agile Methodology and Management using the scrum and sprint framework for product releases and improvement in TOBi ChatBot.

CUSTOMER EXPERIENCE ASSOCIATE | 04/2018 - 02/2019

Vodafone Ghana - Accra, Ghana

Successfully served customers by determining requirements; answering enquiries; resolving problems; fulfilling
requests; maintaining database, determining eligibility to create an outstanding customer experience while ensuring
the attainment of high Quality standards within the Contact Centre

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonyawuni/
- Portfolio https://anthonyawuni.netlify.app/
- Github https://github.com/BuilsaBoy

Education and Training

Exam

Project Management, 02/2023

IPMC IT Training Institute - Accra, Ghana | Some College (No Degree)

Software Engineering, 11/2021

University For Development Studies - Ghana | Bachelor of Arts

Integrated Community Development, 12/2013

Languages

English: First Language